See, if you have a bike or scooter then it is
necessary for you to get it insured.
Many of you might also get your insurance done by going to an agency.
But if you
go to the agency and get any insurance done, that
insurance will be worth ₹1000.
You are already paying the insurance money.
But in the same insurance money, you are
also paying a good commission to that agency.
But when you want to do the same insurance yourself, then
you will not need to pay any commission.  Along with
this, many
additional things are added there.  His
money is also invested.  You do
n't even get to know him.  Apart from this,
you may never use it.  But when you
do it yourself, you will know brother,
what should I take from this and what should I not take
?  Add whatever you need and take it.
Give him his money.  Which is
not needed.  You should not give him money without any reason.
Now the biggest question here will be,
brother, from where should we get insurance
?  Well, there are many companies.  You
can get insurance from many companies from different places.  But for the last several
years, whatever bikes, scooters,
even the Tata PCH car I have,
I insure them all with ECO.
This is the main benefit of taking insurance from Eko,
I even tried it by taking a claim.  Claims
etc. are easily available and
you will be able to get insurance also very easily.
Let me
tell you how to do it.  The process that I am going to tell you now is
for bikes and scooters.  You
can do the same with a car.  For car and
scooty bike, I will put the link of both
in the description.  If you have a
car, then get your car insured.  If it is a
bike or scooter, then you should insure the bike or scooter.
You will get the direct link to get insurance in the description.
As soon as you click on it you will
come to this page.  Here I
will share all the information with you step by step.  I will tell you where to fill up what things
and also the correct method of setting IDB value etc.
so that
you do not make any mistake anywhere.
After coming here, you have to enter your bike number here.
By the way, if you
go to an agency and buy a brand new bike, then
if you take insurance there at that time, the
insurance can be very expensive.
But if you want, you can also get
the insurance of a brand new bike done while sitting there.
You will take the bike.
You tell me, I can do the insurance myself
or I can get it done from outside.
See, here you will get an option to
insure your new bike.  Simply
click on it and select your model here.
Which bike is it, which
model?  If you want, you can insure your bike by entering the Chase number.
My bike is quite old at the moment.  Now
I am going to renew his insurance.
So for this I will simply enter my bike
number here.  Just
after this, you will see the details of your bike here.
Like I have
Hero HF DEDLS bike here, you will get
to see it here.  You will
also get to see which model it is here.  You will
see its passion, here you are
also given the option to set the IDB value.   That
means, you
can increase or decrease it as per your wish.  The less you do, the
lower the premium will be.  The more you
do, the higher the premium will be.  The
best option is to
keep it in the middle.  This is one thing.  The second thing is
that you should check out your previous insurance.
You should keep it a little less than that.
Then it must be less.
Because it always remains the same, whether it is a bike or any other
vehicle.  Its value is bound to go down by at least 10%
as
it gets older.  So for now
I have to set it here as per my requirement.
Its simple emotion will
make you click on continue.  Now you are
asked here that brother, whatever insurance you are going to take here, are you going to take it for
1 year
, 2 years
or 3 years.
The longer you take it, the more likely
you may get a benefit of ₹50.
But you have to make a choice according to your budget as to for
how long you are going to take this insurance.
Now you will see that here I am being
shown two plans, you will see that the
first plan is a compressive plan
which I have taken earlier also.
Apart from this, you can see here that I am
also being given the option of third party plan.  If
I just want to escape from the police and have nothing to do with the bike, then
in that condition I will
go with a third party.  Otherwise, the
best option for me would be the compressive plan.
Even if it costs a little more money.
As you can see here
₹845 is being shown.  ₹714 is being
shown here.  But you get
more benefits in this.  When
you take this plan, third
party is automatically included in it.  So
here I'm going to take the compressive plan.
But let me explain it to you in detail once.
What benefits do you get to see in this so that
you can decide which plan you should
go with.  For now,
we will simply click on More Details.  You will
see it here.  In this you will see that the first thing that is
covered is accidental.  It is
not that if any accident happens with your bike
or your bike gets
damaged badly, it needs to be repaired
, replaced or whatever the damage is,
you will find all those things
covered here.  And
if in any way your
bike catches fire, then that too gets
covered.  Apart from this, see here the
option of tapping is also given.  That means, even
if your bike gets stolen,
you will be able to claim up to your IDB value by filing a claim here.
If there is an
earthquake or any other damage,
you will be able to claim for that also here.
Apart from this, third party
gives injury.  That means if someone gets harmed by your bike, that is, if
any of his belongings
or any property or
his bike, scooter, anything gets
harmed, you will get that covered here too.
By the way, if
someone dies because of you, you can also get that
covered here.  Apart from this,
what other things are not covered?  Let me
clear that up for you as well.  Look,
the first thing here is that if the
tyre tube of your bike has burst or there is
any such problem in the engine, those things will not be
covered.  Please take care.  Apart from this, if
you do illegal driving, for example,
if you are driving your car after drinking here
or are not following the traffic rules, then
you think that the challan will be paid here and the
insurance will be paid here, then this will not happen.
Only two things are not covered here.
After this I simply click on OK.
If you click on third party then
here you will only see that
everything is for third party.  You have
nothing here.  You do
n't get anything here for your bike.  So
what will I do for now?  It is a simple thing here.
I would like to go with the compressive plan.
I have clicked on this here.
After this, see that a coupon
code has been automatically applied here.  Due to which
I will get a discount of ₹150 here.
What do we have to do now?  Simply
click on Continue.  After this,
see here which personal accidental cover you should
take, which is also necessary.  In which
you get insurance up to ₹15 lakh here.  At
present, the
government has also made it mandatory here.
I simply click on the ad.
After this you will see many more things
which I
think you will not need.  So
you can leave everyone else here.  Whereas
if you are going to take the same insurance from any agency or
any third party, they may
add unnecessary things here so that the
amount becomes higher.  The more amount is
made, the more commission will be earned.  For now,
I will simply click on Continue here.
After clicking on Continue,
first of all you have to enter your full name here.  I will
enter the email ID.
Enter mobile number, enter pin code, if you have GST
number, enter GST number.  After this you will simply
click on Continue.
After this,
an OTP will come on the mobile number which you have entered here.  After
entering the OTP, you will simply click on Verify.
After this you will see that
you will get to see all the details here.
Like bike number, bike model,
registration, year, insurance value will also be
visible.
You will also get to see when the policy will start.
You will also get to see for how long the plan is and which plan you have taken.  The
most important thing is that
you can see here that the
payment I have to make is ₹1411, which
I also feel is too much.
Why has it become more now?  Let me
tell you that too.  Apart from this, if you feel that
you are making some mistake here, something
needs to be corrected.  Simply you have to
click on edit here.
We will see now, we had to pay ₹1411 there.  Why is this happening
?  Let me tell you.
After going here, if you feel that
you are facing any problem with the model or the bike here.  If there is
any mistake in selecting something,
you can correct it.
You will also be able to select the model year here.  The main thing is that
if you make a wrong choice here,
your premium increases due to this.
As the first
thing said here is that brother not expired, that is,
if my policy has not expired yet.
I will choose the first one
and I feel that it has expired 90 days ago,
last means it has expired within 90 days, then
I will choose this one and
if it has expired more than 90 days then I will choose this one.
And if I choose this
even by mistake, my premium will increase.
Whereas my policy is going to expire tomorrow.
I will simply
click on Not Expires today because it has
not expired yet.  It will happen tomorrow.  You
see, here I will click on the simple view plan.
After this I will simply
click on Continue.  Now after this,
as I have added it here also.
Now I will click on continue.  Now you
look carefully here, I have to pay ₹1129.
Just mean you have to pay ₹1129.  Whereas
₹1411 had to be paid.  Because
I had selected the wrong things there.
You should keep this thing in mind.  That's why I didn't
select it first and show it to him.
Why if someone does it in a hurry then
later he comes to know that he has suffered a loss of ₹23
because if
your policy expires then
you are charged on it.   You can get
insurance done wherever you go.  Even if you
get it done through any agency,
you will still have to submit the plan there.  So you
must select the right thing there.
Now here it is also asked that
suppose if my policy has not expired then
brother when should this policy start for me.
After this I will simply
click on Continue.  After this, keep in
mind that whatever the GST
amount is, you will also have to pay that GST amount.
Even if you get it done
from an agency or showroom,
you will have to pay GST there too.  So
simply we will make our payment by clicking on Pay Now here.  I will
enter the UPI ID here.  After this
you will simply click on Verify.
Just after this, you will see a notification coming on your application
whatever you have
entered here.  After this,
you can simply make your payment here by clicking on Pay Now.  For
now, let us see that the
payment has been made for our ACCO General Insurance Limited.
After this you will see that your
insurance becomes successful.  Now
where will you download your insurance from
?  Let me show you.   It's
simple, you have to come here.  Click on Go to My
Account.  We
will see after this, I already had a bike here.
I have insured that too.
And now look at the current time, I have insured it here.  You
can simply check your insurance here.   You
can also edit it.  If there is any mistake, you
can also download it.  After this
you will get to see all the information here.
If I simply click on download it.
Here I will click on the PDF document
and whatever
insurance I have will be downloaded here.  Here
I can see and
share all the information.  I can take a printout and keep it
or show it here if needed.
So friends, in today's
video I told you how
you can insure your bike and scooter
, that too while sitting at home.  And here
I shared all the information.  If you
still have any doubts, please let us
know by commenting.  So let's meet again
in the next video.